let's see an intriguing diagram that
gives us five formulas for
pi start with a rectangle with
Dimensions 2 by3 inside the rectangle
draw this triangle as shown here the two
highlighted pink triangles are both 1X
two right triangles so they're congruent
because they fit together at
complimentary angles that means that the
blue shaded triangle is a right triangle
the hypotenuses on the pink triangles
are equal and that means that the blue
triangle has two sides of equal length
therefore the blue triangle is a right
isoceles triangle so the other two
angles are both Pi over4 the pi over4
angle on the left of this diagram can be
obtained as the sum of two angles from
these pictured triangles one of them has
an angle of arctangent 1/3 and the other
one has an angle of arc tangent
1/2 the upper right Pi over4 angle can
be obtained as the difference of two
angles one in this triangle which has an
angle measurement of arctangent 3 and
one in this triangle which has an angle
measurement of AR tangent of a half
another way to get pi over 4 in this
case is as the difference of two angles
in these triangles one with an angle
measurement of arct tangent of two and
the other one with an angle measurement
of the arct tangent of 1/3 the angle in
the upper right corner of the rectangle
is pi/ 2 and this can be obtained as the
sum of three angles where one of them is
the angle measurement of the blue
triangle which is arct tangent one the
next is the arct tangent of 1/2 in this
yellow triangle and the last is the arc
tangent of 1/3 in this yellow
triangle finally the angle on the left
side of the diagram pictured here is pi
and it's the sum of three angles in
three triangles the blue triangle gives
us an angle measurement of arc tangent 1
the bottom yellow triangle here gives us
an angle measurement of arct tangent 2
and the top yellow triangle here gives
us an angle measurement arct tangent
3 this amazing diagram has given us five
formulas for pi let me know in the
comments which of these five you like
the best and check out my Pi playlist
for other videos and animations related
to the circle
constant